# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I will share the recipe of
# 家常牛肉羹
homemade beef soup
# 首先我们准备新鲜的牛里脊肉150克
First, we prepare 150g of fresh beef tenderloin
# 切成小片之后再剁成绿豆大小的颗粒备用
cut the beef into slices before chopping them into half cm size cubes
# 准备老豆腐1小块切成小颗粒备用（约150克）
Prepare 150g of firm tofu and cut it into small cubes for later use
# 同学们最好选择紧实一些的老豆腐这样更香
Firmer tofu is preferred for a richer flavor
# 准备新鲜的香菇2个切成小颗粒备用
Prepare two fresh shiitake mushrooms and dice them into little cubes
# 切香菇的时候也要将香菇蒂留下这样鲜味更浓
add the stems of the mushrooms to enrich the flavor
# 准备适量的海鲜菇切碎备用
Dice few clamshell mushrooms for later use
# 同学们也可以加入各自喜欢的菇类
Other mushrooms can be added based on your preference
# “黑白”菇的加入可以代替味精调节牛肉羹的鲜味
The combination of dark and light colored mushrooms can create a umami flavor, replacing MSG
# 准备适量的香菜切碎备用
rough chop some cilantros for later use
# 不喜欢香菜的同学可以用小葱代替
for those who dislike cilantros, green onions can be a replacement
# 最后准备鸡蛋2个分别将蛋清和蛋黄搅拌均匀备用
lastly, prepare two eggs, whisk the yolks and egg whites separately
# 蛋黄和蛋清分别下锅可以让颜色更有层次
Separating yolks and egg whites renders better visual presentation of the dish
# 下一步开始制作
now we are ready to cook
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
first, we add the right amount of water in the wok
# 再加入适量的食用盐
then add a right amount of salt
# 然后将切好的豆腐，菇类，牛肉粒依次下锅焯水
blanch prepared tofu, mushrooms and beef
# 这一步的目的是去除豆腐的豆腥味
to remove the beany flavor in tofu
# 去除菇类的涩味和牛肉的血沫
astringent flavor in mushroom and blood foams in beef
# 大火烧开之后再撇去浮沫
remove the foams after boiling
# 然后焯好水之后倒出备用
strain the ingredients for later use
# 同学们切记要用到2个漏勺或者改用密漏
use two overlapped strainers or a single strainer with small holes
# 否则会导致竹篮打水一场空
to prevent ingredients from falling out
# 然后在锅中加入适量的纯净水
add filtered water in the wok
# 有条件的同学可以改用清汤
clear stock is also a good option
# 大火烧开之后将焯好水的原料下锅
add blanched ingredients after boiling
# 然后再继续撇去浮沫
remove the excess foams
# 烧至1分钟之后开始调味
cook for 1 minute before seasoning
# 锅中加入适量的食用盐和胡椒粉即可
add a right amount of salt and white pepper powder
# 然后将锅离火加入适量的水淀粉
remote the wok from the stove and add a right amount of slurry
# 把汤汁勾成比米汤略稠的芡即可
till the broth is slightly thicker than congee.
# 重新烧开之后加入准备好的蛋黄和蛋清
bring it to boil and add the whisked yolks and egg whites
# 同学们切记蛋液必须少许慢慢的倒入这样成形更好看
pour the yolks and egg whites slowly for a better visual presentation of the dish
# 在倒入蛋清的时候泡沫会影响美观但不影响食用
foams can form while pouring but doesn’t affect the taste
# 比较介意的同学可以撇去不要
remove the foam if a good visual presentation is required
# 最后在起锅之前加入适量的生抽酱油
add the right amount of soy sauce
# 再加入切好的香菜即可出锅
add chopped cilantro before pouring the soup out of the wok
# 一道营养美味的家常牛肉羹就制作完成
The delicious and nutritious homemade beef soup is done
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，牛肉最好选择里脊或者外脊，这样老人和孩子更加容易消化
# 第二，所有原材料最好事先焯水，这样可以去除大部分的涩味和腥味（豆腥味和牛肉血腥味）
# 第三，水淀粉不能一次性倒入，新手必须少量多次的添加，否则容易过于浓稠无法补救
# 第四，此菜适合四季食用，冬天暖胃夏天消暑，特别适合胃口不好的老人和孩子
# 家常牛肉羹的技术总结完毕
Below is the summary of key points
Firstly, digestive tenderloin is preferred ingredients for this dish
Secondly, blanch the ingredients ahead of time to remove bitterness and beany flavors in tofu and blood foams in beef.
thirdly, pour the slurry slowly to prevent overly thickened broth
Fourthly, this dish is suitable for all seasons. It is stomach warming during the winter and cooling during the summer, best suited for olderlys and children with digestive problems.